Okay, so now in this video I'm going to show you how you can change movement of the player
right according to your own liking.
So if we open up this player related in here as you know that we have this FPS character
and camera, so I'm just going to select both of them and drag and drop them outside.
All right, then I'm going to click on this FPS character.
And on this character as you can see there are many components applied.
So let's just minimize all of them like this.
And then this component called JU character controller controls all of the player movements
all right.
So if you open this up then we're hitting the locomotions if you click on that.
You can now change these values and these values will affect how the player move around
and react with things.
Okay, so if we go ahead and play the game right here we are now as you can see when
we press the W button the player once and then if we hold on shift the player then
walk slow all right and if you try to jump as you can see the jump is really high.
Okay, so we need to fix these things what I'm going to do is I'm going to click escape
to unlock the cursor then click on locomotion in here.
We can change this jump force value to just say three and now if we jump now as you
can see the jump is not that big it is now small jump now after this we need to change
the movement.
So if we turn off this auto run and then also turn off this enable sprint scale right then if
we press the W again now as you can see the player walks slow and if we hold down shift
okay the player doesn't sprint as you can see all right now what we're going to do is
we're going to unlock the cursor click on these three dots right here and copy this component
because we make these changes stop the game make sure that you keep select the FPS character
and right here select these three dots again and then click on paste component values
all right then if you go ahead and play the game again all right the player walk slow
now using the W game if you hold on the shift the player doesn't run all right so if you
click on the commotions let's click on enable sprint scale okay the player doesn't sprint
at all let's turn on the art or run and from the art or run let's remove that take
as well okay now let's remove art or intake as well so now as you can see it is fixed
okay so if we press the W key the player walks low and if we hold shift button now as
you can see the player is sprinting walking slow and then sprinting and jump is also
now smart okay so you need to run on the art or run in disable all of these three options
and then disable art or run as well okay and then the movement will be as we like walking
slow on W key and if you hold on shift the player sprint okay now before closing the game
let's copy this component again close the game and then click on that three dots and click
on paste component values that is all we have to do okay and let me tell you that this player
also has a red tool physics so if you turn on this option which is red tool when press
G or well if you turn that on and start the game even notice that when we press G key
now as you can see the player fall down to the ground like a red tool and then moves up after
few seconds alright so these are different options which you can go ahead and check it out
I have explained few and we also change few things but you can now change other options
as well for example if you increase and decrease the health or you can change these movement
of the player as well as according to your own liking so now with this targets and this video
right here